Alejandro Sabogal Software and Web Developer

954-261-1961 asabogal.dev@gmail.com

alejandro-sabogal.com

github.com/asabogal

Proficient with React, JavaScript, Node/Express, Ruby on Rails. Passionate about bridging creativity and technology. Efficient with smart and responsive Front-End design, and precise at building Back-End architectures. Experienced in Audio Technology, Hospitality, Finance, and Business Administration. Bilingual in English and Spanish.

SKILLS

React, Next.js, Hooks, Context API, Redux, Styled Components, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, Node, Express, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, Postgres, MongoDB, ActiveRecord, RESTful API, MVC Architectures, Google Cloud, Google Firebase, Heroku.

EXPERIENCE

React Developer, Freelance - The Umbrella NYC - Remote/New York, NY | September 2020 - current

- * Developed two Front-End projects with the use of React: antib0dy.club and OffGrid (in progress).
- * Transformed designer frames and slides into working micro-sites with Styled Components and CSS3.
- * Built several custom React Hooks for improved user navigation and site interaction.
- * Architected user onboarding with custom authentication and use of OAuth for Google and Facebook logins.

Next.js and Node/Express Developer, Freelance - kontiki-gp.com - New York, NY | July 2020 - current

- * Designed the UI/UX with React Styled Components and responsive CSS3 grid and flex.
- * Utilized Next.js to architect both the front and back end interfaces.
- * Engineered a Back-End API for a table reservation system and admin center with Node/Express and MongoDB.

Web Developer, Freelance - galleryhotelny.com - New York, NY | July 2019

- * Rebuilt the website from scratch from a templated version to a custom made design with React and Styled Components.
- * Maintained a guest and user database by integrating Google's Firebase.

SELECTED PERSONAL PROJECTS - Additional Projects and Full Portfolio at: alejandro-sabogal.com

Creator, Project - <u>cryptofolio-tracker.com</u> - REACT AND RUBY ON RAILS DEVELOPER - 2019

Interactive Cryptocurrency Portfolio Web App. Fetches real-time and historical crypto data - GitHub Repo

- * Utilized React Context API for state management. React Router for protected and auth routes.
- * Designed the UI/UX with React Styled Components and responsive CSS3 grid/flex.
- * Implemented user authentication with Session Cookies and Bcrypt encryption.
- * Architected the Rails API to persist user and fetched crypto data with PostgreSQL.

Creator, Project - recordbox-reviews.com - RUBY ON RAILS DEVELOPER - 2018

User authenticated vinyl record collection manager web-app - GitHub Repo

- * Architected this Rails only application with MVC design and RESTful patterns.
- * Provided user authentication with the Facebook SDK and OmniAuth with Bcrypt encryption.
- * Utilized Google Cloud Platform and Postgres for data persistence and storage.
- * Chosen as the student highlight project of the Flatiron School's Rails curriculum.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Business Consultant - CRPMNY Property Management - New York, NY 2016 - 2019

Audio Engineer - The Kitchen Studios - Miami, FL | 2011 - 2016

Co-Founder/Owner - PL0T Bookings and Events - Miami, FL | 2008 - 2015

EDUCATION

<u>Full-Stack Software and Web Development</u> - Flatiron School - New York, NY | 2019

Audio Technology and Engineering - SAE Institute of Technology - Miami, FL

Finance and Business Administration - Florida International University - Miami, FL